some medical services association, there was in there with a nice plaque from the organization that
they're annual conference in Squalli State Park. She received it for recognition of her dedication,
passion, and focused to ensuring the safety of citizens that has been with us for about 25 years
and was made the dispatch supervisor and August. I know one of the media outlets came to
interview me, they wanted to talk to Diana Kerva's story, and they said on the aspect of this,
what makes Diana great dispatcher? I see, you know, when people call 911, they are generally
having a really bad day, someone knows the worst time of their life. And to get her on the phone,
and that calming tone, she can calm the situation, and takes care of people through the phone.
Let's know that they're going to get help, she can take care of them, and she just has an amazing
way about her. And from now on, for as perspective, and EMS, she takes very good care of her people. She knows
why I said I think she's psychic. When as a controller on the street, you know, she's going to give you
everything you need, everything you didn't know you need, and get all the information for you to the point
where before you get on the radio, she's going to answer me. Now, this, this, this, this is a check
more, she does, absolutely everything, just her ears of dedication, service, and expertise is very well
deserve this award, and we're very proud of her. Thank you for your excellent service. Congratulations.
Okay, I remember three, as public input and unscheduled personal appearances,
on the audits, it wishes to address the council on any via gender items. You're being known,
item four is considered gender, but then I'm just going to ask you an advantage.
Then staff recommends items five through eight for the consenting, and if there are no questions,
then entertain a motion. May I like the motion, provide a spot through right in the consent agenda.
And a second, second roll call please. All right. All right. All right. All right.
All right. I don't remember nine updates from Abel County Boys and Girls Club. Hi, ladies. How are y'all tonight?
Thank you for having us. Thank you for being here. Yes, thank you very much for having us.
I just wanted to come and give you all an update on our new facility. We have been working since 2013 to
get into the old armory facility down at room.
review park. We have replaced the roof on the flat part of the roof and then we have put
in new heating and air. We're working on the electric right now. We're also working on
painting and taking up the flooring and putting down new flooring and all of that good stuff
that goes along with renovating and building. We also have had a lot of volunteer nights where we've
had a lot of community support come out and help us paint. My eyes racing came out and got the
tile up off the floor. We've had a great community support on this project and so I just want to
say thank you guys once again for allowing us to use that facility as our new home. It's going to be
fabulous. We're going to hopefully be in there in December or January. It's the new date.
And how's your summer program going? It's over. School starts next week. It went great. We had a very good
summer program. They went swimming. They went to the clay station. They went borrowing. They had a lot of
guest speakers come in and talk about various things such as dental hygiene and different careers. It was
a good program. We kept them busy. We had 113 in rolled and then the average was between 65
and 75 depending on if we were swimming or what the fun activity was. Any questions from Melissa?
Thank you, ladies. Thank you. Thank you for the update. I don't think Steve always should do
it sign. Neil? Thank you, Mayor. Mike, would you put, there you go. You read my mind. Actually,
that was the first design that we got back from Kobe a couple of weeks ago. We reached out to Steve and
he actually sent us in pictures that he may like and that was one of them and I think
me and Dean is highly recommending that one. It does two things. It only, it also tributes
to Steve and also Ted Watts. The artist, I think, Ted Watts is probably one of the greatest sports artists
ever. He does get some great work. Unfortunately, he passed away last year. But Ben and Krista
were glad to know that we got permission to use that picture. Steve has all seen all three of
these pictures and he picked that one out. He really likes that one. The only thing that we're going to do
is that University of Oklahoma, we want to enlarge that if I already talked to Kobe about that, that would
be the only change. I think that was the only change one that Dean and we talked about. We also talked
about maybe a little bit.
largely in the lettering for Ted wants to, because the family, we sent this to the family
and they just said that Ted would be thrilled that we're using this.
So they not only granted us permission, but they're just so honored that we're doing that.
So just want to make sure that when people drive by, they see it's not only one great
my, my high school graduate, but too, that we're all in the office building.
This was kind of a rushed deal, and I'll let Dean explain that to a little bit, but I'm
really hard on this, and I apologize to Alicia for getting everything in.
It's the last minute yesterday, I apologize.
But if you all want to look at the other two pictures, we can do that.
Mike, you want to.
Good.
I like that.
I'll make the effect of his color.
I like the first one also.
So what's next?
Good.
Okay.
Well, first off, this is, I think, Colby's talking about just refacing the sign.
It's somewhere in the neighborhood of about $800, so that's something that we can do.
Imagine I'm going to take care of it.
A couple of people were just wondering when this project started.
Well, is this really the city's responsibility in an answer to the question?
Yeah, it's a city sign.
City put that up a few years ago.
Did we refacing about 2006, 2007, somewhere in that neighborhood?
The sign is just worn out.
I mean, that's what it is.
And this goes along the lines of what we're trying to do in Miami to kind of spruce things up.
And I think the artwork is just going to stand out when people come into town now.
It's really going to be a nice improvement of that.
The other thing to point out is that this is the 50th classroom in a CS class in 1966.
And their class reunion is over Labor Day and about a month.
And we've been in touch with Judy Snorley, because Judy's also in that class.
She's helping to put that together.
And what we're hoping is that as part of their classroom union, we can unveil this during that time as part of their class efforts.
And also when we do the unveiling, we want to be sure to invite the Watts family to it.
So Ted's family can be there and be part of that.
And we hope that Steve will be up here for that as well.
So not only to get the sign up, but also just kind of a nice unveiling and showing the community who are kind of renewing our spirit of both what Steve and Ted stand for.
So it's kind of it.
And it's so much fun because this wasn't a grand plan, but one step just left to another and let do another.
And we would step back and say this is just so nice.
So we're pretty happy about this.
Kobe didn't get these pictures till late Friday.
and you don't know if this work in, about a day, day, and a half, so I don't want to thank
Colby.
He, you don't know a lot of great work, initial, mayor, about time.
So I think at this point, I think our plan is that if you give us the bill ahead, we're
going to move full speed ahead, and the next time we'll be talking about it, it's during
the unveiling.
He, Colby, did it so he could have time for everybody, so that's right.
So, do we have an agenda item to vote on or just know that the next meeting you'll bring
a budget item?
Probably it'll be a budget event, but it's really all I need to do, because I think the
expenditure and everything is well-fimmed, what I have of the ability to do.
Question is, Dean, in the packet, and his quote says seven hundred, you want to, well,
it'll be in the budget.
Yeah.
Because I think when Colby gets into it, it'll probably fine-tune his estimate.
Probably.
Yeah.
Do we want to approve this design tonight or...
That's what I'm hoping is that I have a consensus that this is going to be our design and
we move ahead.
We don't need a motion.
It can't hurt.
I make a motion.
We accept the first picture.
The first.
Take a look.
We're kind of calling this the third.
Yeah.
My second that.
That's my favorite too.
There's going to be a little bit of change in the size of the university of Oklahoma.
The same thing is.
That's the picture.
Yes.
Right.
All right.
Good afternoon.
Welcome.
Hello.
Hi.
Thank you.
Thank you, Dean.
I'm an 11-ordance providing delegation authority to wave all our portion of admin fees by written
Resolution Imending Code Section 27-5.
Your honor.
This one is an action item.
Next two are discussion items.
But they really have all three of them relate to items that we've talked about as part of our budget and part of our Comprehensive Plan.
This first one is the waving of fees for this building.
We've talked about that this originally was built.
The building itself was built in 55.
The civic center that we had called the banquet room in 1967.
And this is a civic center.
And part of what our budget intended is that we need to get it back to being a civic center.
Something that the community knows that they're welcome to use that it's available to people.
And really from a financial standpoint for us, our key concern is that we don't have a lot of money on clean up after
Word or a lot of money that we have to put into any type of repair.
But as we're getting some type of rent, what this ordinance does is basically not for profit organizations,
other governmental units, civic clubs like Rotary, Berther Handcakes, Red Cross when they're doing blood drives,
that they know that they can use this facility.
It costs us the same weather we have people.
and if they're not, we would probably set up a structure in which there would be a refundable deposit.
And if everything afterwards cleaned up, we'll give that deposit back immediately.
And just get this building back.
The problem we've had over a number of months that I've been here, and I think before I arrived,
is any time anybody wanted a fee waiver, they had to come to the council.
They had to request permission.
A lot of times where I was worried about it, if we're being consistent in that, this will eliminate that.
Because the code identifies the organizations that are eligible to do that,
I'll have the ability there to get them in, and we can move very a lot quicker.
A couple of things coming up, for example, that are create seminar, the annual seminar.
That's coming up in about a month.
I believe we'll probably have a few things with FERC when they start taking a look at their,
the new flood maps that are coming in, they'll probably want to be using this facility for community meetings.
I've had discussions with some members of our local tribes in which they've referred to me,
and they said, you know, we have to travel events that we'd love to have there,
but we thought we weren't welcome.
And I think we need to make clear now, you're very welcome to come here for those events.
And then ultimately, we could even foresee more events in the gymnasium once we continue to fix this building up
that there could be some elements there.
So that's what this ordinance does, and we recommend we approve it, so we can open the doors to more people.
And it's only this building that we'll talk about.
Correct.
Yes.
Because, you know, getting back to this facility versus, for example, the Coleman Ballroom.
You know, the folks that raised the money for the Coleman Ballroom, the concern there is to be able to raise revenue to continue to support that.
We've kind of struggled with that, and that we really shouldn't be waving the fees for the Coleman for that design.
But we do have an alternative.
And I'll tell you with Jill and her operations and Kevin Browning are doing just step by step.
You can see this building getting refreshed.
And I really enjoying that.
Really appreciate it.
We're just being done.
I'm hoping that next week, if our next council meeting of all goes well, we'll have the 311 Center, the customer service center open.
And I'm hoping it's part of the agenda.
We can take a tour of that.
Not only to see what work has been done, but also just what can be done in this building.
Questions?
Concerns?
Comments?
I think these paid waivers have been a long time ago.
I know that.
Well, I think Dean's point is valid.
This is a civic center.
It's the citizens building.
Yeah.
And I just think perhaps from some of the other facilities.
My concern and I think, at least with the deposit, you're addressing that.
My concern is always, man, things like clean up.
And then if we're incurring an order in a amount of overtime on behalf of a particular organization,
then I think that becomes a concern.
But if we're here to make our business hours.
or regular work hours, not eight to five, but that the staff is here that I'm not personally
as concerned about it.
I have a question.
Will we provide security?
No.
Other than the fact that we have close proximity to police, are there here where our plan is that when
an event takes place here, it's up to the event organizers.
We're making the space available.
Now, we do have a policy, for example, with our police department that people can have officers
there either in a security role or a police department role.
But that's not something that we would be providing, well we're just basically doing this
providing a roof and a good facility for people to use.
Do you have a limitation on the hours that it's going to be available for me?
We really haven't talked about that limitation.
I think to a great degree, we'll be working with Kevin and Jill and her staff on those hours
that come in.
We probably anticipate a lot of them will be during the day.
There may be some weekend items, but with that we even believe that some of the items
we probably will be able to just basically open the door of the facility take place because
the other parts of this facility will lock down and of course we have the police there.
So we don't think it's going to be a burden on staff that it is.
We'll deal with it.
Right now our feeling is that we don't think this will be a big burden on our staff at all.
We're basically telling people, you come in, you take care of it, you clean up, you leave it
the way you found it.
And it's yours.
So we don't want our staff to have to be doing the cleanup or the fix up or anything like that.
Is there a meaning in class for you and your question for there?
Well, I don't think we've had any in a long time that I know.
We started really having this discussion last year when we were doing the Miami 125 or actually
it's earlier this year and getting ready for that and having the F-good rich reunion is when
a lot of us were talking about how, I mean our senior problems were here for you.
Yes, there were some, some of the other events used to be here, the Miami little theater used
to do a place in that room.
So it's just trying to get back to letting those types of organizations know they're welcome.
Well, suppose we can try it for a while and have problems or congenital issues or you visit
the issue.
Mary, I'd like a motion to approve.
Okay.
I'll second.
I'm 12.
Discuss the meaning previous ordinances, which established a $1.50 assessment on municipal utility bills
to fund parks and rent.
Actually, as I was saying, 11, 12 and 13 kind of tie-ins, so I'd probably my comments are
going to be both about 12 and 13, but these are both discussion items.
With an ordinance like this, we thought that you might like to go ahead and look at it and discuss it.
and be able to think about and get me back before we bring you an actual ordinance to take action on,
especially when it's some dealing with a fee that we charge our customers and also one of our
public bodies. But, and again, getting back to our comprehensive planning, getting back to the budget
goals. These are two critical issues that we're discussing. More and more, we're seeing
for a tourism standpoint that sports tourism, especially youth sports tourism, is becoming a very big issue.
And with Amanda's out of town right now, but with Amanda's guidance, we're seeing more and more
events that are taking place in town that relate to our kids, that relate to other teams that want
to come in and play at our facilities. We're talking about our baseball program, softball,
soccer, things such as that. And we spent a great deal of time talking to those entities because
there's always been a concern about the coordination of the programs, which are done by volunteers
and city facilities, which are done by our staff. And the consensus was, they would like to see as a
establish some type of a sports authority with the person that helps with that coordination. And some
programs, for example, the basketball program with the Boys and Girls Club, we keep hearing
every now and then that it might go through a transition when we lost San Wells, not that long ago,
the soccer association ran through some changes. So, this would provide some continuity and it would
also provide a person that would be able to contact and make sure that we can work with these sports
groups to make sure that our facilities are up to speed for. In order to do that, under limited
resources, what we're recommending is that the dollar fifty charge that we had that went to the big
pool, went to the summer program, would be basically broadened to use four parks type programs. And we would
be using those funds to be able to support the coordinator facility for about a three-year period of time.
And it would also, I believe it brings in about 111, 120,000 dollars a year somewhere in that
neighborhood. And we think that will also provide some additional funding just for our parks to keep
our ball fields up to speed. And some things that we've been behind and some preventative maintenance that
will help us catch up. The summer youth program that we've had will continue to go on during this
period of time. But over time, we have about a $160,000 reserve for that program. And we'll just be
basically drawing from that reserve for about a three-year period of time. Now a lot of people are saying
well what happens after the third year with the rep program that we're developing. We believe that will be
able to bring in another source of revenue. Many of these events, many of these tournaments,
there are tournament fees. Some of those fees come into the city and we can turn that around and go back
into this program. So we're being very...
entrepreneurial with that with that item. So that's what we're wanting to do with the dollar
50. We talked about this during the budget that we really need to get started. We need to
make sure that we can get a person on board and start getting the programs up to speed and work
with the council. The other thing that we're suggesting is that and this would be item number 13
is that we enlarge the CBB and disband the parks board. We have a parks board and they basically look
at the parks function. But the proposal that we have right now with the CBB by enlarging it
is that it would become, as we were talking about, recreation programs start tying into convention
and visitors and it becomes a very large source of revenue and it helps our hotels, it helps our
restros, which is the mission of the CBB. To give you a contrasting example of you all
that I came from Branson and you probably seen some of the headlines about how the red roof
mall was being converted into bold items. And it's for exactly that same reason Branson has been
fabulously successful in having these tournaments at the red and blacks and on another company came in
and recognized that they could also have a business model and they took a derelict shopping mall and
are turning it into wallfaces. At a smaller scale we're talking about doing something very similar here,
but it would be nice to have one body like the CBB that not only looks at the recreation
programs, but looks at the broader picture of tourism and visitation in Miami. So oftentimes we talked
about maybe trying to reduce the number of boards we have and this is also an opportunity to do that as
well. So that in essence is what these two items are and we're again only providing them to you tonight
as a discussion on. Something we talked about in budget, but we sleep a few times, we forget about it,
but we've got a lot of work to do if we're going to make this happen and having these ordinances in place
first, gives us that foundation to start working on the program, start working on personnel,
and start making decisions to make this happen. Dean, you may want to find a gel on this but
can you refresh our memory on the purpose of the original $50 funding? My understanding was part of
that went to the renovation of the big pool and the amenities that are there and some restoration that
had to be taken place and that was over a period of time that was some borrowing and paying off. That's been paid off.
And then the other part is the summer record, which we currently have a surplus at and you'll leave the
summer record room, operates on about $50,000 a year, $53,54, and we have a surplus of about 160.
So we've estimated that we have in the bank enough money to be able to run that program for three years.
And we can't use that money for anything else, that's what that money was collected for.
And that's the same program. I mean, we do that collaboration with the Boys and Girls Club, right? Correct.
And it's the college she'll involve.
Yes, they do our harders, our lunches, that.
Okay.
So we want to make it crystal clear, we're not doing anything to affect this program.
Even though we're shifting the funds, we still, this is a very popular program every year.
But we want to, if we can have that three-year window and get this other program, the Recreation Authority program up,
we help the world develop another source of revenue, another channel of revenue by participants, that will help support that,
and then we can channel that dollar fifty back to the summer Recreation Program in about three years.
So we have to perform, there's no two ways about this, and I think Amanda's well aware of that.
But I've also seen a lot of, a lot of very good work done, and I think we can pull that off.
There's so many people that we're talking about trying to do things for our chip for the next generation.
We kind of back away from this, and this is a way to get involved.
One final point is we're not trying to take over the programs.
The programs are run.
We do not have enough resources or time.
This is coordination, but he's talking about the baseball.
The baseball, the soccer, the basketball.
We are not trying to run those programs.
We want to make that crystal clear.
We just want to make sure that we have somebody that can help the signups, have somebody that can coordinate with Jamie,
to make sure that the facilities are in shape, be able to develop some plans to keep the facilities up to speed.
We're already talking to some of the volunteers about some actual capital programs that they've raised funds for,
that we would cooperate with them to improve some of the work facilities.
But also along that line, then it's starting to develop programs like the potential of having tournaments and things such as that.
We're just like the CDB, bringing money from outside the community, inside the community for restaurants.
Our hotels, that's why I was using the boards.
A lot of people travel with their kids to take part in these programs.
I think it's a good idea, but is it in effect the pool at all?
Our pool is not a money maker.
Are we going to be okay there?
The biggest concern I have right now with the pool, the pools and the good shape except for the liner.
That's something that Jamie is telling me that we are releasing some water in the pool every year.
The liner is going to be a big ticket item.
We're really going to have to work through that program.
I think we're losing somewhere in the neighborhood of about 60,000 gallons a day, which sounds like a lot.
But in a pool that day, it's relatively speaking, it's not a week in replace it.
So that's probably one of the risks that we have is that there are going to be some fairly large ticket items on the day pool.
I know that when I got here there were a lot of rumors that we were going to close the day pool.
I've made it crystal clear.
I have some of my favorite memories of the day pool.
So we're going to do our best for that.
Right now we're kind of trying to concentrate on some of the other.
goals and objectives of the comp plan, and that is getting a program like the start itself.
With limited resources, we're trying to channel them into where we can get our best funds.
All right, I agree with Biggie's comments from her.
I mean, the summer-away act program is an awesome program.
It's a great collaboration between the college, the school, the boys, the girls club, and the
city. And I wouldn't want to do anything to harm that. We do have some surplus funds there.
Well, that's correct. You'll comfortable that for a while. And the sports leagues,
they need some admin support on sort of a favor of trying to help them also.
And you'll have a sure board that currently doesn't really have that sports responsibility.
Even picking up two new members. How did they feel about that?
Well, we haven't had that discussion. That's going to be on next 20s.
Okay, Linda. We'll discuss it. This ordinance, I have one concern in one suggestion.
I asked Banyan to look at it in this ordinance. It says you have to be in the city limits.
I have a little bit of concern about that on this board. For an example, and I'm not sure we have one hotel
representative. I think it's very important that we have that on our board.
I think he currently lives outside the city limits. Vimith, things I've been certain about.
The one of the suggestions I made to Ben and I'd like your all-zampot on this. Let me see what number
did. Section 1, 1d. It says the mayor shall nominate subject confirmation about council,
council member to serve at Confucius. I was a voting member of the Advisory Board and it served as a chairperson.
There also can be another city council person. My suggestion or my opinion is that if there is two council
when the other one serves as vice chairman for the purpose of continuity, example,
Brian's on there. When I leave, he can step up and that's just my personal opinion.
But I'll welcome me in my opinion. Other than that, I'm okay with it, I mean.
In your division with your board more. I know there's incident formal conversation.
Right. We have friend new topic form, but you'll discuss it formally at your next meeting.
That would be August. Who's that? Tent?
I believe so. We have the discussion with the CPB when we're put in good intelligence as well.
Your eye is not new, Tent. And you're going to go from salmon to nine.
That's the recommendation. Really, real a thundish. You never really want to board a go beyond nine.
comes in really, but when you look at the breadth of this board, and what we're going to try to accomplish,
nine people, you can have a number of people that have specialties, like Neil was just saying.
People representing hotels, people representing wellness.
A number of things that you could have to tie in and use those resources to put together this branding program.
So it really will help Amanda quite a bit when she starts pulling things together.
And frankly, the CVB, they're a great board to work with right now.
It's got a good bit more people there.
So there's really no action tonight.
They're just in general discussion, and we encourage all of you to read the post-ordinates very closely.
And think about Neil's suggestion that that person, whoever that second council member,
there's a council member that ends up being one there that may be the highest chair in front of New York tonight.
Really helps.
That's a crucial thing.
I am hoping I can bring the formal items to you with next week's board action.
And will you be taking the people off the park board and recording them to?
That's up to you.
That's up to the mayor of the council.
They got suggested to all board members to thank the people who might be interested in serving.
And that's why we won't also discuss next Wednesday.
And we'll make a recommendation to the mayor.
I mean, that's that's the mayor's call.
And we're just going to make a recommendation.
Another part for the struggle is to have a form of a basis.
So at this time, we'll help with that.
It's really pretty exciting to think about how this might look towards the year down the road.
Yeah.
Okay.
It's gotten a lot of measures.
A lot of a couple years I've been on.
Yeah.
Okay.
I had an 14 outside of the organization.
I'm the area economic development service has over the major agreement.
Dean, that's got your name by.
But if you don't mind, I will.
But it's been for probably time for me, but I know.
So gosh, for about two and a half years now, pretty large group of different members of the community have been talking about.
The major organization, the Chamber organization and our community and just how we can keep moving forward and just do a better job.
And concurrent with Judy, it's not really who's been a long time director of the major organization and form that board that she desired to retire in a very near future.
And actually, we kind of pass that deadline, but Judy is stayed around and continue to work.
And she is now.
officially retired, but it's insisting on a part-time basis. But as part of that effort,
what we really figured out are decided that we just need to have better collaboration
between the organization. Just the more what, one group knew about what the other was doing,
the more we could work together, the better. So about a year ago, we started looking for the new
person to lead that organization. We really started the efforts formally about six months ago,
went through, we hired an organization, SGR to assist us in organization that assisted us
when we hired Dean hired then to assist us in that search. And we went through a whole
slew of probably 40 candidates the first time around. We just didn't feel like we found the right
person. So SGR's deal is we'll keep looking till we find the person that you think is the right fit.
So we cast them that again if you will and started with probably 25 people. We narrowed that down
to 8 or 9. We narrowed that down a second time around to about five people and brought those people into
interview. And one of those people is here tonight. Steve Gilbert was hired formally on Monday and I'm
excited about Steve being here. I look forward to all of you getting to know him better. Steve has just
a wealth of experience. It's been a city manager. It was raised in Australia. It was a city manager there
for a while. Had chamber responsibilities in Tulsa, you know significant size organizations.
It's just an economic development experience in Perus checks and some other areas. And so I'm really
excited about him being here tonight or being here in this community here tonight. Steve I'm going to ask
if you would just come up for it to the mic for just a minute. If you want to make a couple of brief comments
and then we will address the agenda item and invite being to make any comments. He might want to.
Thank you Mayor. So I put my hand in my palms. I'm about that. That's it. And I've got poison
ivy on my face. So I'm having trouble. Thank you for having me. And I'm so excited to be here and my family
is I've met several of you and told you about my family. I was like to open the bag box on my kids and my wife.
But we're looking forward to becoming a relocating here. And I've a daughter who'll be in high school
sophomore and talking about youth sports. We've excited about that. So I look forward to continuing
to talk with people and listen and meet folks and and put together the detailed plans to merge
maids and the chamber. And I think as the mayor said, the vision of that is that we can be better
together than we ever were.
separately. I've driven around, I was out at the industrial park today and they're
hanging steel. So I'm excited to be here, look forward to working with you all,
look forward to keeping the city council informed of what's going on, what's
underway, and that's really important that we all stay on the same page and
pull them up in the same direction. So I hope to be here often and have good
things to report and look forward to working with everyone. So thanks for having me.
All right Steve. Thank you.
It was not me to stay in the middle of just pick up to visit with him briefly and I'm
looking forward to some more time with things sitting down visiting with him some more.
Okay.
There's...
Oh, I think just Steve is kind of filling the part of the Jake's salt puzzle we've
been missing in the city. If you go back just maybe three or four days you might have
seen something in the local media about, I believe it was the old junk bakery being
refurbished and reopening. Mayor Nick, or excuse me, Governor Nixon, was in
Joplin and doing ribbon cutting. That was a project that was done through the
Joplin Regional Chamber of Commerce and Rob O'Brien who we've got to be very close to
but accompanying like that will come into a community and they'll have an idea and
you need a person that could put all of the parts together to make that work. Now we
at the city are in very good shape with what Christy McLean has done and heard
part of it in both inspection and economic development. But you also need that
person that is basically coming into the state knowing the state officials, getting
those people that have that idea to come into our community to make that
investment to make it happen. And that's exactly what Steve will be doing. It's
not a situation where Steve will do it and none of us at the city have to. We all have to
be part of it. The other good part of it is too that I think it's going to strengthen the
chain. Michelle Bolton has done a great job but I think a lot of times she needs to have
some help to be able to do things that help our concurrent businesses and help our
current businesses grow. So to have the two formed together I think it's going to make
that a much stronger organization. One that we can work with when the county can work with
and you're talking about the spec building having the iron go up. I like that but I'm really
going to like it when people working in it and that's going to be our goal and objective and then once
that's done we're going to build one right next to it and right next to it. When you look at our
budgets when you look at what we have to deal with we have to grow. We have to create more economic
opportunity in my amma for our future and this is what this is a very positive step in that direction.
Can you, Dean, can you address where it is off to be working? What the plan is going to be off far?
Eventually we're going to figure that out.
I think that's why we're working on that.
So I believe right now you're in the main office
and the first national market we're on the fourth floor
and the chamber is staying where they're at.
But what we hope eventually is as we have some ideas
that we're working on that we'll put everything under one roof
with them once that happens, Amanda is basically
wanting to move to CVB offices to where the chamber is.
And then that will free up two storefronts in the cold
which I know the Shannon makes it very clear.
He's got a waiting list.
So if all these elements come together
which I think they're going to come together very well
we'll have them very close to where we're operating our CVB
our operations and as I said, it'll be seamless.
Okay.
So we have a force, an agreement with Mays
for the coming year
and the amount of $50,000 to provide support for their efforts
do we have a motion to approve that agreement?
I'm like a motion to pre-maring
and that was actually a budget.
Is that correct?
Correct.
Okay.
And do we have a second?
Oh, second.
We'll call.
Before you vote, I should want to point out
that I'm not sure what copy you have in front of.
Okay?
You gave me four boxes.
Okay.
So just for your information,
if you've read the previous draft
there are a few minor changes from this draft
that were requested by Mr. Watson,
who's the attorney who were made.
Basically, while it's implicit in this agreement
that that $50,000
was to be a non-refundable sum.
He asked that that be specifically put in there
so that was added in under paragraph two
on the first page.
Okay.
Then he also requested that we remove
what was paragraph seven
and that provision dealt with
if the city ends up hiring one of their employees
or they end up hiring one of the city employees.
There's a penalty clause for doing that.
He didn't see the need for it.
I just guess that with the need and not.
That's what I know.
And he's seen what's seen the need for that either.
And so those were the substantive changes
there are a couple of other type of graphical changes made.
So this is going to be the agreement
for the fiscal year.
This fiscal year.
Yes, fiscal year.
I fully intend to budget 94 minutes fiscal year
but that determination will be the council
so it's just like all of its beneficiaries.
But I think the organization like this
and this is part of our complaint
and that is to continue this.
support it, we've got to break home the back and we've got to create those jobs, but this is the way you're going to do it.
I'm going to let my wife stay in.
Okay.
Can you do it?
We have a second roll, please.
Jordan.
Hi.
Nice to meet you.
Thank you.
And item 15 is new business.
Do you need new business?
Not on this agenda then.
Item 16 staff reports.
Nothing there.
Item 17, mayor and council announcements.
Any announcements?
Well, welcome.
Stave to my.
What forward to working with you, Steve?
Item 18 city manager communication.
Just three very quick items.
We have a letter dated July 11.
Thanking us for the guns and houses blood drive.
We were able to get 61 points.
And also get our place chief to kiss a pig.
Which was just wonderful.
So very, very good there.
I think you have a picture of that.
Oh, yeah.
They're several.
Several going around.
Yeah.
Really cute pig too.
He was really pretty.
That's a little lipstick.
That's exactly what the pig was wearing.
The other thing is the striping contractor is now taking care of the arterials and they
run fantastic.
Because Mike is taking, or he came back from vacation today, but we're getting that taking care of him.
Had a lot of good comments about that.
And I think with Olson and socials, we're going to be able to do a lot more of that in town too.
But even some people that Neil and Doug and I know that we're kind of wondering what's going on going
out of the way to thank us.
But it's just what you do.
So I'm happy to see that happen.
Last and non-least is tomorrow is the meeting between furt and the inner tribal council.
That is that the Miami complex on Newman Road.
And it starts, I believe, at nine o'clock.
It's kind of slated to end about five.
Not sure how long it actually will take, but I anticipate it's going to be some time.
It's an open meeting.
Everybody is welcome to be at this meeting.
Although the city of Miami will not be a participant, either.
We'll see RDA.
This is strictly between furt and the tribes.
We did do a call and notice.
So if all of you want to attend and you're sitting in the same row,
we have covered our, you know, your participation under the open meetings law.
So you're welcome to be there if you want either for all of it or part of it.
Thank you.
I'm excited about that also.
Okay.
Any other, well, communications?
If not, item 19 is adjourned.
Do we have a most structured chart?
Let's adjourn.
And roll properly.
Second.